<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Study Complexity]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Study Complexity]]></description>
        <link>http://studycomplexity.org/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 00:51:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://studycomplexity.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First step]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>I created a simple model of world order developing. It's too basic to prove anything and there is no underlying data. However, it is useful as a demonstration of a few concepts that are foundational to the rest of my research project. In fact, this might better be described as an animated diagram of how ideas relate to each other.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://studycomplexity.org/first-step/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">cbaa29f2-f473-4e5c-bc29-4190aae06e52</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 00:51:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Last week, Michael Smith and I presented some work we've been doing together on learning analytics at the Military Operations Research Society's 84th Symposium. It's good to get out.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://studycomplexity.org/last-week-michael-smith-and-i-presented-some-work-weve-bee/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">63365702-74e6-4ab8-bbdc-d39bbd5fc4ed</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 22:24:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One step forward and two steps back]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The first challenge from my committee was to build a 'minimal working example' of people acting on behalf of states, a la Colin Wight's concept of 'structural relationsim'. There's not nearly enough there to build a world out of. </p>]]></description>
            <link>http://studycomplexity.org/one-step-forward-and-two-steps-back/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">f9d55347-ead3-4903-895f-5eaa978cfe5d</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 21:30:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Java Maps]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>One of my side projects right now is to use figure out how to do agent-based simulation modeling (ABM) with in-memory data grids (like Hazelcast). A typical ABM assigns a behavior or reflex to agents based on their read of the environment. This usually happens by putting all of the code objects that represent agents into a list and iterating through the list to call on each object/agent to do some observation action, like counting neighbors or detecting a system state. </p>]]></description>
            <link>http://studycomplexity.org/java-maps/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1aee827d-db0f-46b2-a932-831bc911040b</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 21:29:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Studying Complexity in International Relations]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, I defended a proposal to my dissertation committee at George Mason University. I want to model world orders by simulating the social mechanisms that culminate to create it. I think this is important for a host of reasons, most of them related war. </p>]]></description>
            <link>http://studycomplexity.org/studying-complexity-in-international-relations/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b4ccb58e-8d7b-4c65-9735-f60e6320f569</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 17:56:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>